RASHI NIGAM

Summary

I am Senior System Analyst specialized in data, process driven business objectives to transform and present scientific data with more insights to customers, business and project stakeholders. To leverage Data Science and Machine learning algorithm to demonstrate, predict target Key performance indicators and find patterns in data is my core qualification.

Skills

DATA SCIENCE

Exploratory Data Analysis, Visualizatión, Data Wrangling/Cleansing, Feature Engineering, Inferential Statistics, Data Storytelling, Model Analysis, Optimized bootstrapping

Toolkit: Python, SQL, Tableau, Business Objects, OBIEE, CanJS, Reviz, SAP BW, MS Office

STATISTICAL METHODS & MACHINE LEARNING

Classification, Regression, Clustering, Reinforcement Learning, A/B testing, Machine Learning model identification using Hyperparameters Confusion matrix, scikit-learn

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Certifications: PMP, PBA, Scrum

DATABASES

TeraData, Oracle, Vertica, Sql Server, GreenPlum

SERVERS/OS

Linux, Jboss, Tomcat, Apache OS: MAC, Windows, Ubuntu

Education

Springboard Data Science Career Track 2018

Institute of Engineering & Technology, Lucknow, India Bachelors in Computer Science & Engineering 2001

Honors student, IET Alumni

▼ nigamrashi@yahoo.com

4088812100

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nigamrashi/

nashi-n/Machine-Learning-Projects

Employment

Exilant Technologies Inc.

Sr. System Analyst

Cupertino, CA 2015 to Current

- Gathered and analyzed business case for key sales and performance indicators for Customer Systems, Real Estate and iTunes business area
- · Data analysis and visualization to get meaningful insights & present to stakeholders
- Project Managed the infrastructure data/server/app migration objectives for Real Estate, Radar and Support CRM applications
- Technology Stack: Oracle, Vertica/Cassandra/MongoDB, Hadoop, SQL, BO, Can JS, Python, Tableau, Splunk, Github, Linux/Monsoon servers, Radar Apple Requirement/Defect tracker, Espresso/Centralstation, Jumbotron Release scheduler

SRS, Technowiz Consultant @ Fortune 500 Companies System Analyst

2004 to 2014

- · Customer 360 project objective was to highlight data insights from Sales and Finance domain. I built calculation measures to show comparison metrics on Sales & Finance KPI as to deduce Revenue & Profit
- Renewal Opportunity was migration project to bring in-house the process of identifying expiring service contracts due renewal opportunity. I worked to process & data analyze AS-Is vs To-Be system as to ensure this infrastructural change is seamless to Business consumers. Developed system, gap, data specification requirements and Unit Test cases
- Modular Simplified Portfolio project targeted to modularize the Quoting & Pricing of related inventories. I collected the metrics & dimensions business requests, contributed in Design LDM, PDM sessions to come up with optimized UI solution using Business Objects and Tableau.
- Technology Stack: Oracle CRM, Teradata, SQL, BO, Python, OBIEE, Tableau, Salesforce, Github/Sharepoint, Linux/Windows servers, Quality Center/Test Director, MS Project/Office

HCL Perot Systems

Noida, India 2001 to 2003

Software Engineer

- Plant Performance Data warehouse for MDE will provide the Plant performance data for the management to optimize the production and costing through various reports.
- The plant data is recorded in a data control system and necessary data is captured online to generate various reports.
- I created SQL queries & ETL transformations to fetch analyze data from source to target systems.
- Performed Unit and Integration testing and provided Post Production Support.
- Technology Stack: SQL Server, MS SQL, MS Office, RPG IV, DB2, AS400

Projects

Springboard Capstone Project II: Home Credit Default Risk

July 2018 to Aug. 2018

- Predict how capable each applicant is of repaying a loan. Data is publicly made available by client Home Credit for further research and analysis.
- The project research covers data acquisition from Kaggle dataset, data cleansing like missing values, categorical variables, imputation, data storytelling, Exploratory data analysis, inferential statistics and indepth machine learning model evaluation using Pandas, seaboard, numpy, sklearn, Random Forest, Decision Trees. Logistic Regression.
- · Based on research, the risk on repaying a loan could be predicted out of independent feature variables like applicant's education, gender, external data sources. Details on results could be found here.

Springboard Capstone Project I: Bike Sharing Program

May 2018 to May 2018

- · Project objective was to predict the Bike Rental Volume from the dataset given by client Capital Bike Sharing System which posts Quarterly report of bike trip times, start-end locations, user types: Registered vs. Casual.
- In this project I have done data exploratory, statistical analysis, in-depth analysis on machine learning algorithm optimization using Linear Regression, Random Forest to provide data insights like correlation between Independent and Dependent Feature set, Rental Bike Count fluctuation pattern by hour, week, quarter, season, year; by User Type Registered vs. Casual.
- · Results (here) of this project may benefit Client in better prediction of Bike Rental demand.

Housing Prices in Boston Suburbs

April 2018 to April 2018

- · Predict the housing prices based out of in-depth analysis on the The Boston Housing data set which contains information about the housing values in suburbs of Boston.
- I used Linear regression model and predict continuous outcomes with normal random errors. Logistic regression is used to model binary outcomes whereas Poisson regression is used to predict counts. I fitted the Machine learning model using train-test-split. Results of this project are in GitHub.